LYDIA BALASINGH

+91-9945101623 | lydibsingh@gmail.com

Front-End Developer/Visual Designer

PROFILE SUMMARY

Over 11.5 years of IT experience, working as a UI/UX Expert, Front-End Design/Development along with Content Management tools.

Experience in creating Rapid Prototyping using Figma, worked with multiple clients across domains. Having excellent collaboration with other team members & stakeholders.

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGY

- HTML5/CSS3
- Bootstrap4
- WordPress5/Drupal8
- React JS/JavaScript/JQuery
- Adobe CC (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Animate)
- Pixelmator/AutoDesk Graphic
- Corel Draw / 3Ds Max
- Sketch/Figma/Wireframe

CC/Adobe XD

GET-IN-TOUCH

Mobile: +91-9945101623
Email: lydibsingh@gmail.com

LinkedIn: lydia-balasingh

Portfolio: www.coroflot.com/aidyl Website: https://haidyl.github.io/

EDUCATION

-> MCA from Bharathiar University (Karunya Institute of Technology)

CERTIFICATE COURSES

- -> Agile Software Development from Coursera
- -> Web-Centric Computing from NIIT
- -> Virtual Reality from UGC

WEBSITES/WIREFRAMES

https://www.atricure.com https://azurehpc-certification.github.io https://bit.ly/3Pm6TZr http://www.csidivyashanthichurch.net

WORK EXPERIENCE

Capgemini Technology Services India Ltd., Bengaluru as Senior Consultant | Project Lead in Front-End Design (19-Feb-2018 to till date) Currently working for Microsoft Azure HPC client. I am involved in the end to end execution of the GitHub promotion site. Also find below my roles and responsibilities in the current project:

Various Projects handled within Capgemini

1. Type of Industry: Finance (Microsoft)

Project Description: Recreate an all new UX Design for the existing reporting website. Modernization of Data Visualization at every aspect.

Role/Title: Lead - UX Designer

Project Duration: Apr 2022 - Till Date

Responsibilities:

- → Working with the customer for initial requirements
- → Conduct competitive analyses of other websites that operate in the same space
- → Prepare and present rough drafts to internal teams and key stakeholders
- → Develop quick mockups for our development and design team
- → Track usability goals and prepare reports for senior management
- → Coordinate with UI design team

Operating Systems/ Software / Languages: Windows, SharePoint, HTML 5, CSS3, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, PixIr (Online Graphic Editor) Special Tools: Wireframing & UI Design (Figma)

2. Type of Industry: Microsoft Azure Technology (Microsoft)

Project Description: Creation of a static Landing Page which promotes different ISVs of the Microsoft Azure Platform Model. The major task is to convert the normal Word Documentations to creative & interactive HTML Pages.

Role/Title: Module Lead, UI/UX Designer, Word expect (HTML/CSS/Word)

Project Duration: Nov 2021 - Till Date

Responsibilities:

- → Creation of quick Landing pages for GitHub
- → Worked on Mobile Frist Bootstrap Layouts for UI Design.
- → Provide support to the customer during UAT and post production support as part of maintenance
- → Handling Wireframes/Prototypes for the proposed Uls.
- → Worked on Images and Icon creation wherever required to customize the Landing page.
- → Worked on CSS Framework (Bootstrap 4/5) and HTML5 /CSS3
- → Rapid conversion of Word Document to HTML pages in modern UI format.

Operating Systems/ Software / Languages: Windows, SharePoint, HTML 5, CSS3, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, PixIr (Online Graphic Editor) Special Tools: Wireframing & UI Design (Figma)

3. Type of Industry: Learning & Development

Project Description: Creation of a completely new UI for an existing internal webpage in terms of Learning & Development. This Project gives the End User a completely new look & feel of the functionalities related to the Skills, Learnings & Certifications related to the Employees within the Organization Globally according to their Grades & Roles.

Role/Title: Project Manager / UI/UX Designer (SharePoint Platform - Capgemini)

Project Duration: July 2021 - Nov 2021

Responsibilities: End-to-end Project Management as a Scrum Master. Handled the entire project from start to finish (including the Stakeholders requirements to delivery). Along with the Project deliverables, I have taken up the UI Designer role in the project (Complete UI Layout design of the project).

- → Creating project UI Layout for further SharePoint Development
- → Project Goal setting | Tracking | Timelines
- → Regular Documentation of every single tasks and updating the same in DevOps tools.
- → Handling project correspondence at all levels
- → Worked on Images and HTML/CSS wherever required to customize the SharePoint Modern Pages.
- → Worked in complete Agile Methodology with multiple sprints.

Operating Systems/ Software / Languages: Windows, SharePoint, HTML 5, CSS3, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe

Photoshop, PixIr (Online Editor)

Special Tools: Wireframing & UI Design (Figma)

4. Type of Industry: Healthcare (AtriCure)

Project Description: Content management of multiple client websites related to Healthcare. Develop and maintain two-

three websites related to the client requirements. (WordPress/Drupal)

Role/Title: Module Lead / Frond-End Design (Content Management System)

Project Duration: April 2019 – Jun 2021

Responsibilities:

- → Handling an entire Sub-Project (https://www.actagainstafib.com) in CMS (WordPress 5)
- → Working on a major Module Contact Us page with (Gravity Forms)
- → Creating new UI Design with latest Bootstrapping for (https://www.atricure.com/)
- → Delivered 200+ User Stories with 95% On Time Delivery
- → Regular Documentation of every single tasks and updating the same in DevOps tools
- → Handling end to end projects along with latest CMS tools and Front-End Frameworks
- → Coordinate with the Customer and the Onsite counterpart for requirements, Project Estimation and Delivery
- → Working in Agile Methodology
- → Handling project correspondence at all levels
- → Working on Images and Graphics as and when required in the Project accomplishments for each position

Operating Systems / Software / Languages: Windows & Mac, WordPress 5, Drupal 8, Bootstrap 4, PHP, MySQL,

Javascript, jQuery, HTML 5, CSS3

Special Tools: Wireframing (Figma, Zeplin, Sketch, Wireframe CC)

5. Type of Industry: Content Management / Document Management (HP)

Project Description: The HP BI Factory held an existing CMS Web content called Confluence for which a new alternative Creative Web layout was proposed.

Phase I: Wire-framing of the newly proposed Layout

Phase II: UI Designing for the approved wire-framing using Bootstrap.

Phase III: Implementation of the UI Design to a new CMS Tool (WordPress)

Role/Title: GUI Designer / HP BI Factory (UI Designing and CMS)

Project Duration: January 2019 – February 2019

Responsibilities:

- → Detailed review on the existing CMS Tool (Confluence).
- → Creating new Wireframes/Prototypes for the proposed UI.
- → Creating Bootstrap Layouts for HP BI Factory UI Design.
- → Implementation of UI Design in CMS (WordPress).
- → Creating various Icons, Flash GIFs for the Graphical presentations.
- → Creating PowerPoint slides for the project presentations all through the course of the project.

Operating Systems / Software / Languages: Windows 10, Adobe CC, Bootstrap,

Special Tools: Wireframe CC, WordPress

6. Type of Industry: FMCG (P&G)

Project Description:

Module I: Automated font conversion process – To convert the User Inputted Fonts to its relevant substituted Font which is available in the Client's Font Server.

Module II: Image Flattening of Multiple Creative – To flatten the layers of the input files (Adobe Illustrator format) to just 2 layers (Text and Background)

Role/Title: Project Lead / Adobe Illustrator-Visualization (Font Scripting & Image Flattening)

Project Duration: February 2018 – June 2018

Responsibilities:

- → Worked on Automation of Font Scripting and Image Flattening.
- → Reviewing the process of Font Conversion Scripting
- → Handling project correspondence at all levels
- → Team Co-ordination

Operating Systems: Windows 10 | Software / Languages: Adobe Illustrator CC 2017 | Special Tools: Adobe Scripting

Other Work Experiences

Zopsmart Technology Pvt., Ltd., (Zopnow) Bengaluru as *Sr. Graphic Designer in Digital Marketing & Design* (06-Oct-2014 to 31-Jul-2017)

Lead Designer in creating Product Promo Pages, Hoardings and Posters, Website Banners, Mailers, Website layouts, Flex Banners, E-Magazine & Print Magazine, Image Editing, Blogs, Offline Printing. Training Junior Designers in Print/Social Media and Photo Editing.

Suksh Technology Pvt., Ltd., Bengaluru as *Sr. Graphic/Web Designer* (15-Jun-2012 to 25-Apr-2014) Working in E-Commerce Platform was a new eye opener to my career. (Handling Websites, E-Mailers, Google Ads, Promotions, Flash Ads, Website Layout designs)

Kairos Multimedia Pvt., Ltd., New Delhi as Head-Web Designing

(01-Apr-2011 to 31-Mar-2012)

Managed a team of web designers in various overseas Web Projects at various levels. Handled End-End Project Management including (Data collection, PowerPoint/Flash presentations and reviews.)

The Good Samaritans (NGO), New Delhi as SW Programmer/HR Assistant (29-Nov-2004 to 29-Apr-2006) Started my career as a Software Programmer in an NGO gaining lots of experience. It was a dual role. (Developing Software + HR Management)

KEY SKILLS

Functional: UI/UX Designing, Wireframes, Responsive Webpage layouts using HTML5/CSS3, WordPress 5 / Drupal 8 Theming, HTML/CSS e-mailer & web templates, Posters, Hoardings, Banners, Blogs, Logos/Branding, Offline Printing & Flash Ads, Adobe Illustrator Scripting & Automation, Module Lead, Team Building, Team Leader, Customer Relationship, Design/Development, Documentation, Excellent communication and interpretation skills, Azure DevOps, GIT, Agile Methodology. Managing deliverable end to end, along with leading the project by reviewing and testing at all levels.

Technical: HTML 5, CSS3, Bootstrap 4/5, WordPress 5, Drupal 8, SharePoint (Modern Pages), Adobe Creative Cloud (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Animate. XD), Figma, Zeplin, Wireframe CC, JavaScript & jQuery (basic knowledge)

FEATURED IN

- → Professional experience working on commercial software products
- → Proficient in rapid web markups HTML5/CSS3, including CSS3 with latest Bootstrap Framework
- → Perusing knowledge in latest React JS (Redux)
- → Good understanding of server-side CSS pre-processing platform (SASS)
- → Actively handled Blogs, Social Media Pages, HTML Mailer Templates
- → Heading E-Magazines / Offline Printing, Posters
- → Good understanding of SEO principles

- → Conversion of the Word Documentations to creative & interactive HTML Pages
- → Good Knowledge of color rendering
- → Building reusable code and libraries for future use
- → Worked on project executed on Agile Methodology
- → Proficient understanding of code versioning tools, (Git, Azure DevOps)
- → Collaborate with other team members and stakeholders
- → Experience in build/lead teams
- → Effective oral and written communication skills